<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spanish on Europa Español-English Class 2016</title>
    <link>/tags/spanish/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spanish on Europa Español-English Class 2016</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 12:26:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/spanish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter to 1EE parents. Summer term</title>
      <link>/2018/05/29/letter-to-1ee-parents-summer-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 12:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/29/letter-to-1ee-parents-summer-term/</guid>
      <description>Queridos Padres de 1EE,
We hope that you had a nice half term break.
The time goes very quick and as you know it is already the final half term of your child in Year 1. I would like to tell you that everything in 1EE is going very well.The children are improving a lot in all the areas. It will be nice if you know some of the Spanish songs we are listening until now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More information about 1EE</title>
      <link>/2018/05/16/2more-information-about-1ee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/16/2more-information-about-1ee/</guid>
      <description>Queridos Padres de 1EE,
Mainly I am writing you to let you know that everything in 1EE is going very well. The children are improving a lot in all the areas. it will be nice if you know some of the Spanish songs we are listening until now. How you know the songs are a big motivating and resource to learn a language.
&amp;nbsp;
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YGKQxNXQe00
  &amp;nbsp;
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DI4_aM8N2dA
  &amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More information about Spanish lesson</title>
      <link>/2018/04/30/more-information-about-spanish-lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/30/more-information-about-spanish-lesson/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres de 1EE,
We are already in the fourth week of this period. And I think we are getting a good rhythm of learning. As 1EE teacher, I am following the same learning system like Senorita Maria Castro but with some modifications that I consider beneficial with working with children.
Every week I send home homework, between math exercises, reading with Letrilandia or yellow study notebook. I will try to send only one thing each week, because I consider that with the DVDs and a little bit of homework it is enough for the children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email for parents with wma</title>
      <link>/2018/01/31/email-for-parents-with-wma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 11:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/31/email-for-parents-with-wma/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week they are taking Letrilandia home. I have put yellow book too even if it isn&amp;rsquo;t a new page, for those who would like to have a look songs, matific, links&amp;hellip;
In Letrilandia you can review previous letters and you can have a look &amp;quot;s, n, ñ and t.&amp;quot; You can find audio attached.
You can have a look the tales here:
Señorita del silencio: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BQgFQO5uDbs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letrilandia</title>
      <link>/2018/01/10/letrilandia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/10/letrilandia/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres,
Today in their blue bags you will see I haven&amp;rsquo;t send the yellow book. We are starting little by little to recognise letters and sounds in Spanish, we are approaching smoothly to read in Spanish and because of that we have a book where has the letters that we are learning which they are taking home today.
As I told you, this is a world where the letters lives called &amp;quot;Letrilandia&amp;quot;, this week they can show you the real family &amp;quot;u, o, a, e, i&amp;quot; and you can read and look the drawings with them until pag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish book</title>
      <link>/2017/12/13/spanish-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 15:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/13/spanish-book/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres,
This week I have sent the song of the “Real Family” from “Letrilandia” in the yellow book, here you can watch the song: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vViKdsqvDgc
  They may tell you already a story with this letters. It is a “Real Family” and they are different characters. If you go to that link, you can watch in the menu in the right hand side, different songs per letter. I am sure they would like to watch them, at the moment we have seen u, o, a, e, i and p.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>