<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2ee on Europa Español-English Class 2016</title>
    <link>/tags/2ee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2ee on Europa Español-English Class 2016</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 21:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/2ee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Information from the parents meeting (Wednesday 19th September)</title>
      <link>/2018/09/20/information-from-the-parents-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 21:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/20/information-from-the-parents-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents and guardians,
It was great to have a chance to meet most of you on Wednesday. For those who couldn&amp;rsquo;t attend this meeting, please, find attached the presentation that we used that night.
Some reminders:
 Your children can start using Matific at home. Remember you only need to go to the website: matific.com and use your child&amp;rsquo;s name+2ee as a username (for example: jose2ee), and the password is unodos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter in book bag</title>
      <link>/2018/09/07/letter-in-book-bag/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 18:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/07/letter-in-book-bag/</guid>
      <description>Dear All,
What a joy to meet your children! We have had fun.
There is a letter in your child&amp;rsquo;s bag for you tonight and an English reading book. If you feel the reading level is too low, because your child has improved over the holidays, please let us know. We will be checking in with each child in the coming week or so.
Looking forward to meeting you all soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to 2EE</title>
      <link>/2018/09/03/welcome-to-2ee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/03/welcome-to-2ee/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents and Guardians,
We are very much looking forward to welcoming your children in Class 2EE on Wednesday of this week. Sr Ruiz will be in the playground at 8.25 to greet them.
The first week will be making a class display which will include the word “hello” in all of the children’s home languages. It would be great if you could send a slip of paper with your child with the following information:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>