<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2ee on Europa Español-English Class 2016</title>
    <link>/tags/2ee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2ee on Europa Español-English Class 2016</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 17:07:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/2ee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings and fireworks Poem</title>
      <link>/2018/11/09/spellings-and-fireworks-poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 17:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/09/spellings-and-fireworks-poem/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
This week’s words to learn are: 1. head 2. bread 3. meant 4. road 5. coat 6. coach 7. child 8. children 9. wild 10. climb
The first five words will remind the children that when &amp;ldquo;two vowels go together, the first one says its name&amp;rdquo;. The last five words are tricky words from the Year 2 list.
I am also attaching the fireworks poem which the children wrote this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest Schools</title>
      <link>/2018/11/08/forest-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 12:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/08/forest-schools/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents
Re: Outdoor Learning in Year 2
Year 2 are being introduced to the principles of Forest School. We are lucky to have this facility on our site and a member of staff who has trained as a Forest school Leader.
Forest School uses the outdoor environment to support children’s learning across the whole curriculum. The activities specifically follow and enhance the learning from inside the classroom, with a very hands-on approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings</title>
      <link>/2018/11/02/spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 16:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/02/spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Many thanks for supporting your child in learning this week’s words to learn to spell:
 see green week sea each read find kind mind behind  Thanks too to all those of you who are reading on a nightly basis with the children, it makes such a difference. Please do try and ensure that English reading books come back into school each week on a Wednesday so that we can change them for a new one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Comprehension</title>
      <link>/2018/11/01/reading-comprehension/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 17:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/01/reading-comprehension/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Today we have sent home a reading comprehension book to your child as part of this week&amp;rsquo;s homework. Please would you support your child in helping them read the first poem Big Red Boots on page 4 and answering the questions on page 5 as well as they can. This will be challenging for some children as it is a very formal lay out and asks them to answer specific questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half term</title>
      <link>/2018/10/19/half-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/19/half-term/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
We have had a great week with your bright children. I hope they tell you about some of the things they have learnt this week. Ask them about toasting marshmallows in Forest School, or writing instructions about how to make a sandwich &amp;hellip; and then making one. They can tell you about how c and g are scared of i,e and y. They may even be able to fill you in on how to find out the classes favourite sandwich - as a bar chart, or a tally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half term Spanish Homework</title>
      <link>/2018/10/17/half-term-spanish-homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/17/half-term-spanish-homework/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents and guardians,
The children have been very busy at the biginning of this first term learning some words and vocabulary to provide a context for future learning (getting to know the school, classroom supplies, parts of the body, adjectives, food, etc.). Please, help them keep doing so by doing their homework and finding opportunities to ask them about what they have learnt at school.
This week we are sending the first book in a bag as reading homework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings for Ladybirds</title>
      <link>/2018/10/11/spellings-for-ladybirds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/11/spellings-for-ladybirds/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Thanks for all your help in supporting your child&amp;rsquo;s learning of spellings last week, they were thrilled to show their learning in class today.
The words to learn for the coming week are: 1. made 2. came 3. same 4. take 5. safe 6. five 7. ride 8. door 9. poor 10. floor
As you can see, this week the pattern is words containing the vowel phonemes using split digraphs a_e and i_e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Film shown in assembly today</title>
      <link>/2018/10/10/film-shown-in-assembly-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/10/film-shown-in-assembly-today/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Your children&amp;rsquo;s work was shown in assembly today and I thought you might like to see it. Class 2EE made beautiful film riddles using their senses and lots of adjectives - they described two places in the school and challenged the other children to guess where they had been.
To see the films just click on the link below or cut and paste it into your internet browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings for test next Thursday</title>
      <link>/2018/10/04/spellings-for-test-next-thursday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/04/spellings-for-test-next-thursday/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Many thanks for supporting your child in learning their spellings. This week’s words to learn practice the ai and oi sound. The last two words are from the tricky word list.
 rain wait train paid oil join coin point Mr Mrs  Have fun together playing with sounds.
Warmest wishes,
Liz Cook</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings for next week</title>
      <link>/2018/09/27/spellings-for-next-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 17:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/27/spellings-for-next-week/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents and Guardians,
Thank you for working so hard to help your children learn their spellings last week. We had a test in class today and they were thrilled to share with each other the ingenious ways they had practised.
For the coming week the spellings are the words for numbers from eleven to twenty.
 eleven twelve thirteen fourteen fifteen sixteen seventeen eighteen nineteen twenty  Have fun with your children in rainbow letters, air writing, in the car &amp;hellip; the test is in school next Thursday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings for 2EE</title>
      <link>/2018/09/22/spellings-for-2ee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 17:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/22/spellings-for-2ee/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents
Please find below the spellings for next Thursday’s spelling test in Class 2EE.
 one two three four five six seven eight nine ten  The children completed a spelling assessment yesterday and I will be marking it over the weekend so that we can provide differentiated levels of spellings from next week.
Apologies for the delay in these reaching you, I thought schoolbase had sent this to you previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information from the parents meeting (Wednesday 19th September)</title>
      <link>/2018/09/20/information-from-the-parents-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 21:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/20/information-from-the-parents-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents and guardians,
It was great to have a chance to meet most of you on Wednesday. For those who couldn&amp;rsquo;t attend this meeting, please, find attached the presentation that we used that night.
Some reminders:
 Your children can start using Matific at home. Remember you only need to go to the website: matific.com and use your child&amp;rsquo;s name+2ee as a username (for example: jose2ee), and the password is unodos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter in book bag</title>
      <link>/2018/09/07/letter-in-book-bag/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 18:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/07/letter-in-book-bag/</guid>
      <description>Dear All,
What a joy to meet your children! We have had fun.
There is a letter in your child&amp;rsquo;s bag for you tonight and an English reading book. If you feel the reading level is too low, because your child has improved over the holidays, please let us know. We will be checking in with each child in the coming week or so.
Looking forward to meeting you all soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to 2EE</title>
      <link>/2018/09/03/welcome-to-2ee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/03/welcome-to-2ee/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents and Guardians,
We are very much looking forward to welcoming your children in Class 2EE on Wednesday of this week. Sr Ruiz will be in the playground at 8.25 to greet them.
The first week will be making a class display which will include the word “hello” in all of the children’s home languages. It would be great if you could send a slip of paper with your child with the following information:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>