<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Announcements on Europa Español-English Class 2016</title>
    <link>/categories/announcements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Announcements on Europa Español-English Class 2016</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 16:46:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/announcements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings and story</title>
      <link>/2019/03/15/spellings-and-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 16:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/15/spellings-and-story/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Science week has been fun! The children used microscopes on Wednesday, assisted by a research scientist Oxford University. On Thursday they learnt about animal behaviour from Luca’s Mum and loved hearing about positive rewards helping rescue animals learn to behave. In Maths they have made 3D shapes and in English they have learnt how to tell the Chinese story of Mai Ling. Please do ask them to tell you the story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings and SATs papers</title>
      <link>/2019/03/02/spellings-and-sats-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 09:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/02/spellings-and-sats-papers/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Class 2EE had a great week this week, I hope they have already told you about the helicopter seeds they made to understand seed dispersal, plant art with cardboard pieces, measuring g, kg, ml and litres and writing about their magic gardens. We welcomed a new child to our class, Ariadne joined us just in time to celebrate her birthday.
Spellings this week are the or sound spelt as a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SATs presentation this evening</title>
      <link>/2019/02/27/sats-presentation-this-evening/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/27/sats-presentation-this-evening/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Many thanks to those of who were able to join us this evening to learn more about the national UK Year 2 assessments. If you were unable to attend, please do ask the other parents for their feedback.
Please find attached the powerpoint presentation which we shared.
It would be wonderful if you could support your child over the coming months prior to May in becoming confident to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SATs info eve tomorrow 5pm, Book Fair competition and fancy dress</title>
      <link>/2019/02/26/sats-info-eve-tomorrow-5pm-book-fair-competition-and-fancy-dress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/26/sats-info-eve-tomorrow-5pm-book-fair-competition-and-fancy-dress/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
I hope you had a relaxing and happy half term. This is just a note to say I am looking forward to seeing you for the SATs INFORMATION EVENING in 2EE classroom tomorrow at 5pm.
Next week the BOOK FAIR will be held in the chapel every day from 15.45 until 16.15. Please come and support the school by buying a book if you can.
Linked to the book fair there is a COMPETITION to design an A4 extraordinary/interesting word poster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poet&#39;s ribbons and Times Table certificate</title>
      <link>/2019/02/15/poets-ribbons-and-times-table-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 16:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/15/poets-ribbons-and-times-table-certificate/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
This week the children wrote number poems, baked bread on a camp fire, learnt about penguins and played maths games with shapes. There are no spellings for half term, but two challenges.
Challenge 1 – POET’S RIBBON To learn a poem by heart. Any child able to share their poem by heart after the break will win a poet&amp;rsquo;s ribbon for their book bag. I attach a few poems to choose from but any poem they love will do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dates for your diary and spellings</title>
      <link>/2019/02/08/dates-for-your-diary-and-spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/08/dates-for-your-diary-and-spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
We have had fun this week making food chains, finding out about left over M&amp;amp;Ms, writing colour poems, learning about Hanukkah, playing Guess Who and making a Forest School Canopy.
Words to learn for spelling this week are:
 fly
 sky
 pie
 mice
  5.high
6.might
7.night
8.tights
9.sigh
10.sight
You child has brought home some of these on light bulbs to play with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings</title>
      <link>/2019/01/25/spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 19:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/25/spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
The children have had a busy week creating habitat posters, playing with 5 x tables, making handprints in the forest, dividing up cookies, modelling animals in clay and thinking from inside the head of a robin, crab, frog or squirrel. The classroom is full of their wonderful creations.
This week’s words to learn for spellings are:
 tie
 pie
 cry
 try
 dry
 cried</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New reading books</title>
      <link>/2019/01/10/new-reading-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 11:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/10/new-reading-books/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents,
Thank you so much for all of your effort and contributions to buy new books for our classroom.
Yesterday we sent lots of new books in your kids&amp;rsquo; reading bag to read at home. Please, write some commnets on their reading log about their reading as they read the book, and don&amp;rsquo;t worry if they don&amp;rsquo;t finish to read the whole book in a week, they can be hold at home to read at your/your child&amp;rsquo;s convenience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings</title>
      <link>/2018/12/07/spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 19:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/07/spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Your children have been a joy to teach this week. They have learned lots about how to make slime and how to choose which materials would be best for an umbrella or a bouncy ball. They have painted pine cones from the tree in forest schools and worked with clay in art. If you are cutting up pizzas ask them if fractions need to be equal. They know about halves, quarters and thirds … and quite a bit more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest School and Spellings</title>
      <link>/2018/11/22/forest-school-and-spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/22/forest-school-and-spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
The children had a fascinating time today playing with real money hot off the press from De La Rue.
  They have brought home a pencil made of old bank notes to show you. Tomorrow we will be enjoying testing out building with materials to see if they are waterproof in Forest Schools. Please do make sure that your child has suitable clothing. It will be cold and possibly wet Gloves, hats, warm coats and waterproof trousers are ideal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building houses with materials</title>
      <link>/2018/11/15/building-houses-with-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/15/building-houses-with-materials/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
I thought you might like to see some pictures from the building work today. The children worked immensely hard responding to a brief, designing, budgeting, building, testing and adapting their houses. They learnt a lot about working in teams, keeping within a timeframe and learning from mistakes. I hope they mentioned it to you. They should be very proud of their hard work. Attached are two compilation photos, excuse the mix being a little rushed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings</title>
      <link>/2018/11/15/spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 11:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/15/spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
The children are having a great day building houses for the three little pigs today. They are working as teams to design, budget, build and test their houses to see if they can withstand the wolf&amp;rsquo;s blowing. This is why we did our spelling test early yesterday.
The spellings to learn for next week are as follows:
 food
 moon
 school
 good
 book
 took</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings and fireworks Poem</title>
      <link>/2018/11/09/spellings-and-fireworks-poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 17:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/09/spellings-and-fireworks-poem/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
This week’s words to learn are: 1. head 2. bread 3. meant 4. road 5. coat 6. coach 7. child 8. children 9. wild 10. climb
The first five words will remind the children that when &amp;ldquo;two vowels go together, the first one says its name&amp;rdquo;. The last five words are tricky words from the Year 2 list.
I am also attaching the fireworks poem which the children wrote this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Film shown in assembly today</title>
      <link>/2018/10/10/film-shown-in-assembly-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/10/film-shown-in-assembly-today/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Your children&amp;rsquo;s work was shown in assembly today and I thought you might like to see it. Class 2EE made beautiful film riddles using their senses and lots of adjectives - they described two places in the school and challenged the other children to guess where they had been.
To see the films just click on the link below or cut and paste it into your internet browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information from the parents meeting (Wednesday 19th September)</title>
      <link>/2018/09/20/information-from-the-parents-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 21:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/20/information-from-the-parents-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents and guardians,
It was great to have a chance to meet most of you on Wednesday. For those who couldn&amp;rsquo;t attend this meeting, please, find attached the presentation that we used that night.
Some reminders:
 Your children can start using Matific at home. Remember you only need to go to the website: matific.com and use your child&amp;rsquo;s name+2ee as a username (for example: jose2ee), and the password is unodos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter in book bag</title>
      <link>/2018/09/07/letter-in-book-bag/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 18:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/07/letter-in-book-bag/</guid>
      <description>Dear All,
What a joy to meet your children! We have had fun.
There is a letter in your child&amp;rsquo;s bag for you tonight and an English reading book. If you feel the reading level is too low, because your child has improved over the holidays, please let us know. We will be checking in with each child in the coming week or so.
Looking forward to meeting you all soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to 2EE</title>
      <link>/2018/09/03/welcome-to-2ee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/03/welcome-to-2ee/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents and Guardians,
We are very much looking forward to welcoming your children in Class 2EE on Wednesday of this week. Sr Ruiz will be in the playground at 8.25 to greet them.
The first week will be making a class display which will include the word “hello” in all of the children’s home languages. It would be great if you could send a slip of paper with your child with the following information:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More details about school trip</title>
      <link>/2018/06/18/more-details-about-school-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 15:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/18/more-details-about-school-trip/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres,
Tomorrow is our year1 joint end-of-year school trip to Cotswold Wildlife Park, Tuesday 19th of June.
Children will need to bring a small backpack on the day, where they can keep their lunch (picnic provided by the canteen regarding your child&amp;rsquo;s lunch routine at school) and their bottle of water.
As the weather forecast looks to be good you may want to provide them with a hat, and put some sun cream on in the morning (before school).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>more information about the trip</title>
      <link>/2018/05/29/more-information-about-the-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 16:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/29/more-information-about-the-trip/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres,
I forgot to tell you the following:
Children will need to bring a small backpack on the day, where they can keep their lunch (own pack lunch or picnic provided by the canteen regarding your child&amp;rsquo;s lunch routine at school) and their bottle of water.
If the weather forecast looks to be good you may also want to provide them with a hat, and put some sun cream on in the morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter to 1EE parents. Summer term</title>
      <link>/2018/05/29/letter-to-1ee-parents-summer-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 12:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/29/letter-to-1ee-parents-summer-term/</guid>
      <description>Queridos Padres de 1EE,
We hope that you had a nice half term break.
The time goes very quick and as you know it is already the final half term of your child in Year 1. I would like to tell you that everything in 1EE is going very well.The children are improving a lot in all the areas. It will be nice if you know some of the Spanish songs we are listening until now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More information about 1EE</title>
      <link>/2018/05/16/2more-information-about-1ee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/16/2more-information-about-1ee/</guid>
      <description>Queridos Padres de 1EE,
Mainly I am writing you to let you know that everything in 1EE is going very well. The children are improving a lot in all the areas. it will be nice if you know some of the Spanish songs we are listening until now. How you know the songs are a big motivating and resource to learn a language.
&amp;nbsp;
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YGKQxNXQe00
  &amp;nbsp;
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xbnYmgsTFio
   &amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More information about Spanish lesson</title>
      <link>/2018/04/30/more-information-about-spanish-lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/30/more-information-about-spanish-lesson/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres de 1EE,
We are already in the fourth week of this period. And I think we are getting a good rhythm of learning. As 1EE teacher, I am following the same learning system like Senorita Maria Castro but with some modifications that I consider beneficial with working with children.
Every week I send home homework, between math exercises, reading with Letrilandia or yellow study notebook. I will try to send only one thing each week, because I consider that with the DVDs and a little bit of homework it is enough for the children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documents from phonics screening meeting</title>
      <link>/2018/04/27/documents-from-phonics-screening-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 16:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/27/documents-from-phonics-screening-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents
As discussed at the meeting we are sending you the presentation that we shared with you and the list of sample words, which can be used for practise at home. The words include all the sounds that we have covered this year - the phase 3 and 5 sounds.
Download presentation
Download sample words
Unfortunately the presentation becomes slightly corrupted on saving, however all the information can be read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonics screening notes</title>
      <link>/2018/04/25/phonics-screening-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 22:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/25/phonics-screening-notes/</guid>
      <description>Hi,
I took some notes at the phonics screening meeting this evening - I thought they might be useful to share with the whole class group via email.
The teachers are going to circulate the powerpoint slides from the meeting and some examples of the words they will have to read,
 Phonics Screening is a national &amp;lsquo;test&amp;rsquo; that takes place in Year 1 in the second week in June.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parents&#39; meeting regarding Year 1 phonics screening</title>
      <link>/2018/04/13/parents-meeting-regarding-year-1-phonics-screening/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/13/parents-meeting-regarding-year-1-phonics-screening/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
We would like to invite you to a short meeting at 6-6:30 pm on Wednesday the 25th of April regarding the statutory Year 1 phonics screening which will take place in early June. We plan to meet in the Drama Studio at the bottom of the large tower block.
At the meeting we will outline the nature of the the screening program and suggest ways that you can support your child with their phonics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Term / New Teachers</title>
      <link>/2018/04/11/new-term-new-teachers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/11/new-term-new-teachers/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents,
I hope that you had a nice half term break.
I have the pleasure introducing myself, I am Francisca Moreno, new Spanish teacher. Some parents know me because I am working in REE (Spanish in Reception) from September.
We have another new teacher for this class, Cristian is a Sport teacher in Primary who is going to teach Physical Depelovement and Arts being on Monday (12.30 pm to 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Felices vacaciones</title>
      <link>/2018/03/21/felices-vacaciones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 16:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/21/felices-vacaciones/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week you can see in the yellow book two new pages:
 Song about &amp;ldquo;La señorita Z&amp;rdquo; and picture of &amp;ldquo;La enfermera C&amp;rdquo;. This two letters have the same sound (like a snake), when Z goes with a, u, o and when C goes with e and i.
 Song about &amp;ldquo;La señorita Z&amp;rdquo;: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-HZsQylt8xE      
 Song about &amp;ldquo;La enfermera C&amp;rdquo;: https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books this week</title>
      <link>/2018/03/14/books-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/14/books-this-week/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week we have seen two new characters in Letrilandia which sounds the same in Spanish (b and v) the children are taking Letrilandia home to read them with you. (audio attached, pag 45 and 47).
 pag 45: La presumida B - download audio
 pag 47: El camarero V - download audio
  In the yellow book you will see different words written with b and v, please try to write with them as last week you did with y and ll.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links this week</title>
      <link>/2018/03/07/links-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 15:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/07/links-this-week/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week I have sent in the yellow book words written with &amp;ldquo;y / ll&amp;rdquo;. Although they have the same sound your child should write them in the correct way. Read with them and you can ask them to write you different words on a paper. Another activity you can do is to read it to them and your child can find the picture or opposite (They read it to you and you can find the picture).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellow book and yellow folder</title>
      <link>/2018/02/28/yellow-book-and-yellow-folder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/28/yellow-book-and-yellow-folder/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week I am sending home the yellow book with a nice song about the seasons:
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0lEMEzDMdVI 
   
On the other hand I have sent homework in the yellow folder. They have to check how it is the weather every day and they should write the full sentence in Spanish. If they need it, they can look in the yellow book (last week entry), I am sure it will help them to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email for parents with wma</title>
      <link>/2018/01/31/email-for-parents-with-wma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 11:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/31/email-for-parents-with-wma/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week they are taking Letrilandia home. I have put yellow book too even if it isn&amp;rsquo;t a new page, for those who would like to have a look songs, matific, links&amp;hellip;
In Letrilandia you can review previous letters and you can have a look &amp;quot;s, n, ñ and t.&amp;quot; You can find audio attached.
You can have a look the tales here:
Señorita del silencio: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BQgFQO5uDbs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letrilandia</title>
      <link>/2018/01/10/letrilandia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/10/letrilandia/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres,
Today in their blue bags you will see I haven&amp;rsquo;t send the yellow book. We are starting little by little to recognise letters and sounds in Spanish, we are approaching smoothly to read in Spanish and because of that we have a book where has the letters that we are learning which they are taking home today.
As I told you, this is a world where the letters lives called &amp;quot;Letrilandia&amp;quot;, this week they can show you the real family &amp;quot;u, o, a, e, i&amp;quot; and you can read and look the drawings with them until pag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish book</title>
      <link>/2017/12/13/spanish-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 15:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/13/spanish-book/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres,
This week I have sent the song of the “Real Family” from “Letrilandia” in the yellow book, here you can watch the song: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vViKdsqvDgc
  They may tell you already a story with this letters. It is a “Real Family” and they are different characters. If you go to that link, you can watch in the menu in the right hand side, different songs per letter. I am sure they would like to watch them, at the moment we have seen u, o, a, e, i and p.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>