<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Announcement on Europa Español-English Class 2016</title>
    <link>/categories/announcement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Announcement on Europa Español-English Class 2016</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 18:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/announcement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings</title>
      <link>/2019/01/18/spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 18:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/18/spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Your children have written owl books, multiplied with arrays, painted with straws, laid footprint traps, explored habitats, learnt about Judaism and more this week. They’ve been busy!
On Thursday we visited the Library and the children were invited to take a book home. I have a list of the books they have borrowed. There is no pressure at all for the children to read the books, they may enjoy you reading to them or they may just want to dip in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas!</title>
      <link>/2018/12/20/merry-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 16:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/20/merry-christmas/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Thanks so much to those of you who provided food and drink for the children&amp;rsquo;s jewel party today. We had music, dancing, film and bubbles. I&amp;rsquo;ve attached some photos for you to enjoy.
In the children&amp;rsquo;s book bags are clay stars and Christmas poems they have made as presents, as well as Christmas cards they have made too. Please do hunt them out.
I have sent home Reading Comprehension books/ Phonics books depending on your child&amp;rsquo;s level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No spellings!</title>
      <link>/2018/12/14/no-spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 18:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/14/no-spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
The children have worked so hard this week I think we should not do a spelling test next week.
It was lovely to see some of you at the concert on Monday and on Wednesday evening. Many thanks for your generosity to Snr Ruiz and I - I have some very lovely presents to put under the tree.
Some of you asked me to send you a copy of the tricky words which your child should be able to spell by the end of the year in their own writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming events</title>
      <link>/2018/11/28/coming-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/28/coming-events/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents and guardians,
Next week we will be working on the elaboration of some objects using some of the materials that we have studied in our science lessons (wood, plastic, cotton, wool, metal, stone, etc.). We will ask the children to make something using at least 3 different materials. Please help your children find something they can bring and maybe plan ahead in time what object they can make at school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest Schools</title>
      <link>/2018/11/08/forest-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 12:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/08/forest-schools/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents
Re: Outdoor Learning in Year 2
Year 2 are being introduced to the principles of Forest School. We are lucky to have this facility on our site and a member of staff who has trained as a Forest school Leader.
Forest School uses the outdoor environment to support children’s learning across the whole curriculum. The activities specifically follow and enhance the learning from inside the classroom, with a very hands-on approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings</title>
      <link>/2018/11/02/spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 16:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/02/spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Many thanks for supporting your child in learning this week’s words to learn to spell:
 see green week sea each read find kind mind behind  Thanks too to all those of you who are reading on a nightly basis with the children, it makes such a difference. Please do try and ensure that English reading books come back into school each week on a Wednesday so that we can change them for a new one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Comprehension</title>
      <link>/2018/11/01/reading-comprehension/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 17:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/01/reading-comprehension/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Today we have sent home a reading comprehension book to your child as part of this week&amp;rsquo;s homework. Please would you support your child in helping them read the first poem Big Red Boots on page 4 and answering the questions on page 5 as well as they can. This will be challenging for some children as it is a very formal lay out and asks them to answer specific questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half term</title>
      <link>/2018/10/19/half-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/19/half-term/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
We have had a great week with your bright children. I hope they tell you about some of the things they have learnt this week. Ask them about toasting marshmallows in Forest School, or writing instructions about how to make a sandwich &amp;hellip; and then making one. They can tell you about how c and g are scared of i,e and y. They may even be able to fill you in on how to find out the classes favourite sandwich - as a bar chart, or a tally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last weeks of this course</title>
      <link>/2018/06/25/last-weeks-of-this-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 11:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/25/last-weeks-of-this-course/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres de 1EE
We are only two weeks away from finishing this course, but we are still learning many things every day. I inform you that from today the children will send the finished work home being: red notebooks, the yellow notebook, math books and other work. So they are asked to take each day out of the blue backpack and stay home. In that way we avoid that the children do not arrive with a lot of weight at home.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>