<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Español on Europa Español-English Class 2016</title>
    <link>/tags/espa%C3%B1ol/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Español on Europa Español-English Class 2016</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 18:54:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/espa%C3%B1ol/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading book</title>
      <link>/2020/03/02/reading-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 18:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/02/reading-book/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
This Friday we will start reading the book &amp;ldquo;Cuando trabajé en el circo&amp;rdquo; in class. In case you bought the book, please remind your child to bring it on Friday.
Thanks
Sofia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carnival this Friday</title>
      <link>/2020/02/24/carnival-this-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/24/carnival-this-friday/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
I hope you all had a lovely break. Just to inform you that this Friday we will be celebrating Carnival in class so children can come to school dressed up if they would like to, it would be nice and we will have a small party at the end of the day.
Thanks
Sofia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PE clothes</title>
      <link>/2020/01/23/pe-clothes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/23/pe-clothes/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
This email has been sent to me from the PE teacher to pass on to all of you.
Dear parents,
Since the beginning of the school year I agreed that children could wear comfortable clothes on their PE day to avoid getting changed for PE. Nevertheless, they end up getting their trousers, socks and shoes quite wet and muddy during breaks, and consequently they end up bringing the dirt into the gym.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 3 trip on the 30th Jan to Science Oxford</title>
      <link>/2020/01/19/year-3-trip-on-the-30th-jan-to-science-oxford/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 17:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/19/year-3-trip-on-the-30th-jan-to-science-oxford/</guid>
      <description>Dear year 3EE parents,
We are pleased to let you know there will be a school trip to Science Oxford on Thursday 30th January to carry out some hands on experiments and observe other scientific phenomena. https://scienceoxford.com/centre/visitor-information/
The coaches will depart promptly at 9am. Children will require a packed lunch and water bottle that day, please ensure they have a small rucksack or bag to carry this in.
We will need two parent helpers for the trip so let me know if you are free and would like to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading book tomorrow</title>
      <link>/2020/01/08/reading-book-tomorrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 21:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/08/reading-book-tomorrow/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
I hope you all had a really nice time at Christmas.
Tomorrow we will start reading the book &amp;ldquo;Cartas a Raton Perez&amp;rdquo; in class. In case you bought the book, please remind your child to bring it tomorrow.
Thanks
Sofia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas song</title>
      <link>/2019/12/01/christmas-song/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 13:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/01/christmas-song/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
Please see below the link for the Christmas song that we are practising in class for the concert, in case someone can&#39;t find it. It can be found on youtube under the name &amp;ldquo;Campana sobre campana, Juana, Villancico Clasico (Animado) - Canticuentos.
  I also asked them that if they have small bell/sleigh bell it would be good if they could bring it with them for the song.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish topics, websites and reading books</title>
      <link>/2019/12/01/spanish-topics-websites-and-reading-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 11:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/01/spanish-topics-websites-and-reading-books/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
Some parents wanted to know the topics we will be learning this year in Spanish. You can see this below, so you can also support them with this at home:
 Family Descriptions Pats of the body Jobs Christmas in Spain Clothes The weather Nationalities, where people are from Carnival Our town Shops Plants, life cycle of plants Animals, habitats, life cycles Semana Santa, Easter in Spain Food, in the restaurant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE Parents evening location - room 99 NOT the classroom</title>
      <link>/2019/11/18/3ee-parents-evening-location-room-99-not-the-classroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 21:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/18/3ee-parents-evening-location-room-99-not-the-classroom/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents,
Please come to room 99 for parents evening appointments, not the classroom. As we will be starting appointments when the classroom is in use then all of the meetings will be in room 99 which is in the hostel block, opposite the Thame Lane reception office. There will be a few chairs outside to wait on.
Many thanks,
Ruthy Trevitt and Sofia Morton</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading books</title>
      <link>/2019/09/28/reading-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 10:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/28/reading-books/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
I think some parents have bought the books I mentioned. Thanks a lot for this, it is much appreciated and the children will benefit. It would be good to know what books the children have as I would like to use them in the class with them.
For this reason I would appreciate if they could bring the book(s) they&#39;ve got in to class with their names on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading and resources</title>
      <link>/2019/09/18/reading-and-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 19:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/18/reading-and-resources/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
I hope this email finds everyone well. As I mentioned at parents evening, for children that finish reading the class book quickly and would like to read a longer book, I would suggest some books from this website:
More difficult reading (8- 10 years old): link
Less difficult reading (6- 8 years old): link
They are really good as they have lots of activities and resources on the internet for each book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>/2019/09/15/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 10:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/15/reading/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
This year we will be working with some books to read in class and do some activities from. It would be good if they can continue reading them at home at the same time as it would help their comprehension and vocabulary.
See below the list of reading books we will be using each term if you would like to get them.
Autumn:
 Ricardo y el dinosaurio rojo   Cuando me converti en lobo  Spring:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science next week</title>
      <link>/2019/03/27/2019-03-27t141200-science-next-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/27/2019-03-27t141200-science-next-week/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents,
This week we have been learning about plants we eat during our science lessons. The children have been learning that we may eat either a root (carrot, beetroot,&amp;hellip;), a stem (celery, asparagus,&amp;hellip;), leaves (lettuce, spinach, &amp;hellip;), flowers (artichoke, coliflower, brocoli, &amp;hellip;), seeds (peas, beans, &amp;hellip;), etc.
We are planning to do a healthy snack lesson on Monday trying to combine all of these products in a green salad. We would appreciate if you could pack for your child some of these products in small ziplock bags or tupper, ideally chopped in long sticks or ready to eat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New reading books</title>
      <link>/2019/01/10/new-reading-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 11:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/10/new-reading-books/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents,
Thank you so much for all of your effort and contributions to buy new books for our classroom.
Yesterday we sent lots of new books in your kids&amp;rsquo; reading bag to read at home. Please, write some commnets on their reading log about their reading as they read the book, and don&#39;t worry if they don&#39;t finish to read the whole book in a week, they can be hold at home to read at your/your child&#39;s convenience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half term Spanish Homework</title>
      <link>/2018/10/17/half-term-spanish-homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/17/half-term-spanish-homework/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents and guardians,
The children have been very busy at the biginning of this first term learning some words and vocabulary to provide a context for future learning (getting to know the school, classroom supplies, parts of the body, adjectives, food, etc.). Please, help them keep doing so by doing their homework and finding opportunities to ask them about what they have learnt at school.
This week we are sending the first book in a bag as reading homework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last weeks of this course</title>
      <link>/2018/06/25/last-weeks-of-this-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 11:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/25/last-weeks-of-this-course/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres de 1EE
We are only two weeks away from finishing this course, but we are still learning many things every day. I inform you that from today the children will send the finished work home being: red notebooks, the yellow notebook, math books and other work. So they are asked to take each day out of the blue backpack and stay home. In that way we avoid that the children do not arrive with a lot of weight at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More details about school trip</title>
      <link>/2018/06/18/more-details-about-school-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 15:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/18/more-details-about-school-trip/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres,
Tomorrow is our year1 joint end-of-year school trip to Cotswold Wildlife Park, Tuesday 19th of June.
Children will need to bring a small backpack on the day, where they can keep their lunch (picnic provided by the canteen regarding your child&#39;s lunch routine at school) and their bottle of water.
As the weather forecast looks to be good you may want to provide them with a hat, and put some sun cream on in the morning (before school).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>more information about the trip</title>
      <link>/2018/05/29/more-information-about-the-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 16:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/29/more-information-about-the-trip/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres,
I forgot to tell you the following:
Children will need to bring a small backpack on the day, where they can keep their lunch (own pack lunch or picnic provided by the canteen regarding your child&#39;s lunch routine at school) and their bottle of water.
If the weather forecast looks to be good you may also want to provide them with a hat, and put some sun cream on in the morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter to 1EE parents. Summer term</title>
      <link>/2018/05/29/letter-to-1ee-parents-summer-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 12:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/29/letter-to-1ee-parents-summer-term/</guid>
      <description>Queridos Padres de 1EE,
We hope that you had a nice half term break.
The time goes very quick and as you know it is already the final half term of your child in Year 1. I would like to tell you that everything in 1EE is going very well.The children are improving a lot in all the areas. It will be nice if you know some of the Spanish songs we are listening until now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More information about 1EE</title>
      <link>/2018/05/16/2more-information-about-1ee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/16/2more-information-about-1ee/</guid>
      <description>Queridos Padres de 1EE,
Mainly I am writing you to let you know that everything in 1EE is going very well. The children are improving a lot in all the areas. it will be nice if you know some of the Spanish songs we are listening until now. How you know the songs are a big motivating and resource to learn a language.
 https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YGKQxNXQe00
   https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xbnYmgsTFio
   https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More information about Spanish lesson</title>
      <link>/2018/04/30/more-information-about-spanish-lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/30/more-information-about-spanish-lesson/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres de 1EE,
We are already in the fourth week of this period. And I think we are getting a good rhythm of learning. As 1EE teacher, I am following the same learning system like Senorita Maria Castro but with some modifications that I consider beneficial with working with children.
Every week I send home homework, between math exercises, reading with Letrilandia or yellow study notebook. I will try to send only one thing each week, because I consider that with the DVDs and a little bit of homework it is enough for the children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Term / New Teachers</title>
      <link>/2018/04/11/new-term-new-teachers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/11/new-term-new-teachers/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents,
I hope that you had a nice half term break.
I have the pleasure introducing myself, I am Francisca Moreno, new Spanish teacher. Some parents know me because I am working in REE (Spanish in Reception) from September.
We have another new teacher for this class, Cristian is a Sport teacher in Primary who is going to teach Physical Depelovement and Arts being on Monday (12.30 pm to 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Felices vacaciones</title>
      <link>/2018/03/21/felices-vacaciones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 16:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/21/felices-vacaciones/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week you can see in the yellow book two new pages:
  Song about &amp;ldquo;La señorita Z&amp;rdquo; and picture of &amp;ldquo;La enfermera C&amp;rdquo;. This two letters have the same sound (like a snake), when Z goes with a, u, o and when C goes with e and i.
 Song about &amp;ldquo;La señorita Z&amp;rdquo;: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-HZsQylt8xE      Song about &amp;ldquo;La enfermera C&amp;rdquo;: https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books this week</title>
      <link>/2018/03/14/books-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/14/books-this-week/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week we have seen two new characters in Letrilandia which sounds the same in Spanish (b and v) the children are taking Letrilandia home to read them with you. (audio attached, pag 45 and 47).
  pag 45: La presumida B - [download audio](/audio/Pag 45 La presumida B.wma)
  pag 47: El camarero V - [download audio](/audio/Pag 47 El camarero V.wma)
  In the yellow book you will see different words written with b and v, please try to write with them as last week you did with y and ll.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links this week</title>
      <link>/2018/03/07/links-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 15:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/07/links-this-week/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week I have sent in the yellow book words written with &amp;ldquo;y / ll&amp;rdquo;. Although they have the same sound your child should write them in the correct way. Read with them and you can ask them to write you different words on a paper. Another activity you can do is to read it to them and your child can find the picture or opposite (They read it to you and you can find the picture).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellow book and yellow folder</title>
      <link>/2018/02/28/yellow-book-and-yellow-folder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/28/yellow-book-and-yellow-folder/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week I am sending home the yellow book with a nice song about the seasons:
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0lEMEzDMdVI    On the other hand I have sent homework in the yellow folder. They have to check how it is the weather every day and they should write the full sentence in Spanish. If they need it, they can look in the yellow book (last week entry), I am sure it will help them to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email for parents with wma</title>
      <link>/2018/01/31/email-for-parents-with-wma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 11:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/31/email-for-parents-with-wma/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week they are taking Letrilandia home. I have put yellow book too even if it isn&#39;t a new page, for those who would like to have a look songs, matific, links&amp;hellip;
In Letrilandia you can review previous letters and you can have a look &amp;quot;s, n, ñ and t.&amp;quot; You can find audio attached.
You can have a look the tales here:
Señorita del silencio: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BQgFQO5uDbs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letrilandia</title>
      <link>/2018/01/10/letrilandia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/10/letrilandia/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres,
Today in their blue bags you will see I haven&#39;t send the yellow book. We are starting little by little to recognise letters and sounds in Spanish, we are approaching smoothly to read in Spanish and because of that we have a book where has the letters that we are learning which they are taking home today.
As I told you, this is a world where the letters lives called &amp;quot;Letrilandia&amp;quot;, this week they can show you the real family &amp;quot;u, o, a, e, i&amp;quot; and you can read and look the drawings with them until pag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish book</title>
      <link>/2017/12/13/spanish-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 15:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/13/spanish-book/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres,
This week I have sent the song of the “Real Family” from “Letrilandia” in the yellow book, here you can watch the song: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vViKdsqvDgc
  They may tell you already a story with this letters. It is a “Real Family” and they are different characters. If you go to that link, you can watch in the menu in the right hand side, different songs per letter. I am sure they would like to watch them, at the moment we have seen u, o, a, e, i and p.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>