<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Europa Español-English Class 2016</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Europa Español-English Class 2016</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 15:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>More details about school trip</title>
      <link>/2018/06/18/more-details-about-school-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 15:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/18/more-details-about-school-trip/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres,
Tomorrow is our year1 joint end-of-year school trip to Cotswold Wildlife Park, Tuesday 19th of June.
Children will need to bring a small backpack on the day, where they can keep their lunch (picnic provided by the canteen regarding your child&amp;rsquo;s lunch routine at school) and their bottle of water.
As the weather forecast looks to be good you may want to provide them with a hat, and put some sun cream on in the morning (before school).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>more information about the trip</title>
      <link>/2018/05/29/more-information-about-the-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 16:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/29/more-information-about-the-trip/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres,
I forgot to tell you the following:
Children will need to bring a small backpack on the day, where they can keep their lunch (own pack lunch or picnic provided by the canteen regarding your child&amp;rsquo;s lunch routine at school) and their bottle of water.
If the weather forecast looks to be good you may also want to provide them with a hat, and put some sun cream on in the morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter to 1EE parents. Summer term</title>
      <link>/2018/05/29/letter-to-1ee-parents-summer-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 12:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/29/letter-to-1ee-parents-summer-term/</guid>
      <description>Queridos Padres de 1EE,
We hope that you had a nice half term break.
The time goes very quick and as you know it is already the final half term of your child in Year 1. I would like to tell you that everything in 1EE is going very well.The children are improving a lot in all the areas. It will be nice if you know some of the Spanish songs we are listening until now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More information about 1EE</title>
      <link>/2018/05/16/2more-information-about-1ee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/16/2more-information-about-1ee/</guid>
      <description>Queridos Padres de 1EE,
Mainly I am writing you to let you know that everything in 1EE is going very well. The children are improving a lot in all the areas. it will be nice if you know some of the Spanish songs we are listening until now. How you know the songs are a big motivating and resource to learn a language.
&amp;nbsp;
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YGKQxNXQe00
  &amp;nbsp;
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DI4_aM8N2dA
  &amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio</title>
      <link>/audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/audio/</guid>
      <description> Srta Maria&amp;rsquo;s Spanish audio recordings from Letrilandia  Letrilandia pag 19
 Letrilandia pag 21
 Letrilandia pag 23
 Letrilandia pag 25
 Letrilandia pag 27
 Letrilandia pag 29
 Letrilandia pag 31
 Letrilandia pag 41 La y griega
 Letrilandia pag 43 El portero LL
 Letrilandia pag 45 La presumida B
 Letrilandia pag 47 El camarero V
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More information about Spanish lesson</title>
      <link>/2018/04/30/more-information-about-spanish-lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/30/more-information-about-spanish-lesson/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres de 1EE,
We are already in the fourth week of this period. And I think we are getting a good rhythm of learning. As 1EE teacher, I am following the same learning system like Senorita Maria Castro but with some modifications that I consider beneficial with working with children.
Every week I send home homework, between math exercises, reading with Letrilandia or yellow study notebook. I will try to send only one thing each week, because I consider that with the DVDs and a little bit of homework it is enough for the children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documents from phonics screening meeting</title>
      <link>/2018/04/27/documents-from-phonics-screening-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 16:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/27/documents-from-phonics-screening-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents
As discussed at the meeting we are sending you the presentation that we shared with you and the list of sample words, which can be used for practise at home. The words include all the sounds that we have covered this year - the phase 3 and 5 sounds.
Download presentation
Download sample words
Unfortunately the presentation becomes slightly corrupted on saving, however all the information can be read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonics screening notes</title>
      <link>/2018/04/25/phonics-screening-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 22:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/25/phonics-screening-notes/</guid>
      <description>Hi,
I took some notes at the phonics screening meeting this evening - I thought they might be useful to share with the whole class group via email.
The teachers are going to circulate the powerpoint slides from the meeting and some examples of the words they will have to read,
 Phonics Screening is a national &amp;lsquo;test&amp;rsquo; that takes place in Year 1 in the second week in June.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emails</title>
      <link>/email/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/email/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parents&#39; meeting regarding Year 1 phonics screening</title>
      <link>/2018/04/13/parents-meeting-regarding-year-1-phonics-screening/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/13/parents-meeting-regarding-year-1-phonics-screening/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
We would like to invite you to a short meeting at 6-6:30 pm on Wednesday the 25th of April regarding the statutory Year 1 phonics screening which will take place in early June. We plan to meet in the Drama Studio at the bottom of the large tower block.
At the meeting we will outline the nature of the the screening program and suggest ways that you can support your child with their phonics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Term / New Teachers</title>
      <link>/2018/04/11/new-term-new-teachers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/11/new-term-new-teachers/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents,
I hope that you had a nice half term break.
I have the pleasure introducing myself, I am Francisca Moreno, new Spanish teacher. Some parents know me because I am working in REE (Spanish in Reception) from September.
We have another new teacher for this class, Cristian is a Sport teacher in Primary who is going to teach Physical Depelovement and Arts being on Monday (12.30 pm to 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>Videos This is a collection of videos (available via YouTube) referred to by teachers in the kids&amp;rsquo; Spanish red (REE) and yellow (1EE) workbook. For REE, a link to the YouTube video playlist is available. Single embedded videos will be added soon. For 1EE, single embedded videos are provided and a link to the YouTube video playlist is available.
You can choose to either subscribe to the linked playlist via your own YouTube account so that the video playlist can be available to you when you go into your own YouTube account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos</title>
      <link>/videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/videos/</guid>
      <description>Reception Year Video playlist A playlist of all reception year videos can be found via this link:
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLFWfEkn3frrWYvABgU4TzPRFMuBoRzeCm
 
Year 1 Días de la semana
   
Meses del año
   
El monstruo de los colores
   
El Monstruo de los colores videocuento
   
Las partes del cuerpo
   
Las partes del cuerpo - Barney El Camion</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calendar</title>
      <link>/calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:48:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/calendar/</guid>
      <description>
 
 1EE Events Birthdays Europa School Events  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is the home of the Europa School Español-English Class of 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Felices vacaciones</title>
      <link>/2018/03/21/felices-vacaciones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 16:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/21/felices-vacaciones/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week you can see in the yellow book two new pages:
 Song about &amp;ldquo;La señorita Z&amp;rdquo; and picture of &amp;ldquo;La enfermera C&amp;rdquo;. This two letters have the same sound (like a snake), when Z goes with a, u, o and when C goes with e and i.
 Song about &amp;ldquo;La señorita Z&amp;rdquo;: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-HZsQylt8xE      
 Song about &amp;ldquo;La enfermera C&amp;rdquo;: https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books this week</title>
      <link>/2018/03/14/books-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/14/books-this-week/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week we have seen two new characters in Letrilandia which sounds the same in Spanish (b and v) the children are taking Letrilandia home to read them with you. (audio attached, pag 45 and 47).
 pag 45: La presumida B - download audio
 pag 47: El camarero V - download audio
  In the yellow book you will see different words written with b and v, please try to write with them as last week you did with y and ll.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links this week</title>
      <link>/2018/03/07/links-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 15:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/07/links-this-week/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week I have sent in the yellow book words written with &amp;ldquo;y / ll&amp;rdquo;. Although they have the same sound your child should write them in the correct way. Read with them and you can ask them to write you different words on a paper. Another activity you can do is to read it to them and your child can find the picture or opposite (They read it to you and you can find the picture).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellow book and yellow folder</title>
      <link>/2018/02/28/yellow-book-and-yellow-folder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/28/yellow-book-and-yellow-folder/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week I am sending home the yellow book with a nice song about the seasons:
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0lEMEzDMdVI 
   
On the other hand I have sent homework in the yellow folder. They have to check how it is the weather every day and they should write the full sentence in Spanish. If they need it, they can look in the yellow book (last week entry), I am sure it will help them to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email for parents with wma</title>
      <link>/2018/01/31/email-for-parents-with-wma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 11:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/31/email-for-parents-with-wma/</guid>
      <description>Hola a todos,
This week they are taking Letrilandia home. I have put yellow book too even if it isn&amp;rsquo;t a new page, for those who would like to have a look songs, matific, links&amp;hellip;
In Letrilandia you can review previous letters and you can have a look &amp;quot;s, n, ñ and t.&amp;quot; You can find audio attached.
You can have a look the tales here:
Señorita del silencio: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BQgFQO5uDbs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letrilandia</title>
      <link>/2018/01/10/letrilandia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/10/letrilandia/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres,
Today in their blue bags you will see I haven&amp;rsquo;t send the yellow book. We are starting little by little to recognise letters and sounds in Spanish, we are approaching smoothly to read in Spanish and because of that we have a book where has the letters that we are learning which they are taking home today.
As I told you, this is a world where the letters lives called &amp;quot;Letrilandia&amp;quot;, this week they can show you the real family &amp;quot;u, o, a, e, i&amp;quot; and you can read and look the drawings with them until pag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish book</title>
      <link>/2017/12/13/spanish-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 15:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/13/spanish-book/</guid>
      <description>Queridos padres,
This week I have sent the song of the “Real Family” from “Letrilandia” in the yellow book, here you can watch the song: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vViKdsqvDgc
  They may tell you already a story with this letters. It is a “Real Family” and they are different characters. If you go to that link, you can watch in the menu in the right hand side, different songs per letter. I am sure they would like to watch them, at the moment we have seen u, o, a, e, i and p.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>