<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3EE on Europa Español-English Class 2016</title>
    <link>/tags/3ee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3EE on Europa Español-English Class 2016</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 13:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/3ee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 3 Easter Experience trip cancelled</title>
      <link>/2020/03/16/year-3-easter-experience-trip-cancelled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/16/year-3-easter-experience-trip-cancelled/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents,
In light of the current situation with the Corona virus the Easter Experience at Trinity Church has been cancelled. The trip was due to happen on Thursday 26th March.
Many thanks,
Year 3 team</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 3 animal research project</title>
      <link>/2020/03/16/year-3-animal-research-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 13:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/16/year-3-animal-research-project/</guid>
      <description>Dear year 3 parents,
In case of school closure please find attached a research project which we usually carry out over the Easter holidays in the lead up to our trip to Beale Park. Whilst the trip may not now happen, as nothing can be assured at this time, it would be good for the children to have a chance to carry out this research.
This research will be used after the scheduled Easter holidays to put together a presentation in both the stream language and English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE work for 16th-18th March for those in self-isolation</title>
      <link>/2020/03/15/3ee-work-for-16th-18th-march-for-those-in-self-isolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 23:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/15/3ee-work-for-16th-18th-march-for-those-in-self-isolation/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
Please find attached the plans and resources for the English part of the coming week with 3EE.
Expect your child to come home with maths workbooks which should be brought back into school Mon-Wed each week and remain at home the rest of the time. Although they are heavy A4 books it means if the school is suddenly closed or you have to self isolate then you have the main resources for our maths lessons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE lessons on bereavement for PSHE this week</title>
      <link>/2020/03/14/3ee-lessons-on-bereavement-for-pshe-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 21:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/14/3ee-lessons-on-bereavement-for-pshe-this-week/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents
This week 3EE will have PSHE lessons exploring bereavement, giving children a space to pause and reflect and to ask questions. I have attached the lesson resources we will be using so that if your child is absent you have the opportunity to explore this area with them at home. The resource is taken from Child bereavement UK.
If your child would rather not be in these lessons please let me know - I have timetabled them for a time when Louise, our TA, is with us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE Access to computer or tablet at home</title>
      <link>/2020/03/14/3ee-access-to-computer-or-tablet-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 08:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/14/3ee-access-to-computer-or-tablet-at-home/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
In case schools are asked to close by the UK government we are making contingency plans as a school. As part of this it would be helpful to know if your child/children have access to a tablet or computer that they can use to access virtual lessons (most likely to be done via google hangouts) and can access set tasks and submit their work via google classroom. Please email Sofia and I if your children do not have a computer or tablet that they can use at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE PE lessons for the rest of the year</title>
      <link>/2020/03/11/3ee-pe-lessons-for-the-rest-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/11/3ee-pe-lessons-for-the-rest-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
We are doing PE on Monday 16th March (a second aerobics and dance session) then the following week the second PE lesson will be swimming.
3EE have a total of 10 Friday swim sessions as set out below:
27th Mar
3rd Apr
24th Apr
1st May
15th May
22nd May
5th Jun
12th Jun
19th Jun
26th Jun
Children will need a cap, towel, goggles and full swim suits: bikinis or loose swim shorts are not suitable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE Science Week - next week 9-13 March</title>
      <link>/2020/03/04/2020-03-04t163900-3ee-science-week-next-week-9-13-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/04/2020-03-04t163900-3ee-science-week-next-week-9-13-march/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
It is science week next week. I am sorry this is a little last minute but if you feel you as a parent could come in next week and share a science experiment or activity with the class please let Sofia and I know what it is and when you might be able to come in. Good times to share experiments are first thing in the morning 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading book</title>
      <link>/2020/03/02/reading-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 18:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/02/reading-book/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
This Friday we will start reading the book &amp;ldquo;Cuando trabajé en el circo&amp;rdquo; in class. In case you bought the book, please remind your child to bring it on Friday.
Thanks
Sofia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE helpful spelling app, times table practice, cake sale confusion</title>
      <link>/2020/02/28/3ee-helpful-spelling-app-times-table-practice-cake-sale-confusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 13:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/28/3ee-helpful-spelling-app-times-table-practice-cake-sale-confusion/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
Firstly apologies for any confusion over the cake sale, cakes can be brought in on Wednesday in advance of the sale which will be held on Thursday and Friday next week. Timestables practice is available on Timestables rockstars, https://play.ttrockstars.com/ your child&#39;s username is the first letter of their first name followed by the first three letters of their surname and then the digits 30; everybody&#39;s password is currently set as rockstar3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 3 cake sale arrangements for next Thursday and Friday</title>
      <link>/2020/02/28/year-3-cake-sale-arrangements-for-next-thursday-and-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 12:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/28/year-3-cake-sale-arrangements-for-next-thursday-and-friday/</guid>
      <description>Dear year 3 parents,
Our cake sale is coming up on Thursday and Friday next week, we&#39;ve put up posters and got our baking tins out in preparation. In order that the bus children in year 3 do not miss out on their own cake sale we would like to invite them to bring in £1 and choose a cake on Thursday 5th March, children not travelling on the bus may also do this if it is more convenient for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carnival this Friday</title>
      <link>/2020/02/24/carnival-this-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/24/carnival-this-friday/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
I hope you all had a lovely break. Just to inform you that this Friday we will be celebrating Carnival in class so children can come to school dressed up if they would like to, it would be nice and we will have a small party at the end of the day.
Thanks
Sofia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cake sale to raise money for year 3</title>
      <link>/2020/02/23/cake-sale-to-raise-money-for-year-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/23/cake-sale-to-raise-money-for-year-3/</guid>
      <description>Dear year 3 parents,
We are very pleased we were able to book an extra trip this term to visit Narnia at Dorchester Abbey. With 3EE going on Tuesday 3rd March, 3DE on Wednesday 4th March and 3FE going on the 5th March it should be a great experience for all. However, because it is an extra trip we need to cover a shortfall in the costs by raising some money through a year 3 cake sale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basketball clubs to continue interest from PE lessons</title>
      <link>/2020/02/11/basketball-clubs-to-continue-interest-from-pe-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 10:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/11/basketball-clubs-to-continue-interest-from-pe-lessons/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
We have been very lucky to have Ernest Guevarra come in each Monday to teach the children basketball as one of their PE lessons. As the children will all too soon be starting swimming as a second PE lesson, we are nearing the end of these basketball sessions. Many of the children have really developed their skills and enjoy playing the sport. If they would like to continue with this interest there is a link here to basketball clubs in Oxfordshire which you could pursue with your child: https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE request for lego boards and pieces to build Narnia maps</title>
      <link>/2020/02/09/3ee-request-for-lego-boards-and-pieces-to-build-narnia-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 21:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/09/3ee-request-for-lego-boards-and-pieces-to-build-narnia-maps/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
This Tuesday afternoon we are planning to build 3D maps of Narnia to help us both in planning and writing our own adventure story in Narnia but also to assist us in learning mapping techniques. We will aim to build a 3D map, turn it into a 2D map and use it as inspiration for our own Narnia stories. If you and your children are able to help by lending Lego and base boards on Tuesday and Wednesday this week (11th and 12th February) that would be great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE parent helpers request for trips</title>
      <link>/2020/02/06/3ee-parent-helpers-request-for-trips/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 13:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/06/3ee-parent-helpers-request-for-trips/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
If you would like to help on any of the remaining trips please let me know. Two of them are just morning trips rather than the whole day. We currently have need of:
One more adult for Narnia at Dorchester Abbey on Tuesday 3rd March 9:00-13:15
Three adults for the Trinity Church, Abingdon, Easter Experience on Thursday 26th March 9:00-11:30
One more adult (ideally with some Spanish language) for Beale Park (a wildlife park) on Tuesday 12th May 9:00-15:00</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 3 Narnia Trip and Cake Sale fundraiser</title>
      <link>/2020/02/05/year-3-narnia-trip-and-cake-sale-fundraiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/05/year-3-narnia-trip-and-cake-sale-fundraiser/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
We are very excited to inform you about a trip to the Narnia Exhibition at Dorchester Abbey which links to our English book this term, &amp;lsquo;The Lion, the Witch and the Wardrobe&amp;rsquo;, see https://www.dorchester-abbey.org.uk/narnia-2/ for more information. The trip will take place on Tuesday 3rd March for 3EE, with the coach departing at 09:00 and returning at 13:15.
Packed lunches will be needed for all children on the day of their trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PE clothes</title>
      <link>/2020/01/23/pe-clothes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/23/pe-clothes/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
This email has been sent to me from the PE teacher to pass on to all of you.
Dear parents,
Since the beginning of the school year I agreed that children could wear comfortable clothes on their PE day to avoid getting changed for PE. Nevertheless, they end up getting their trousers, socks and shoes quite wet and muddy during breaks, and consequently they end up bringing the dirt into the gym.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 3 trip on the 30th Jan to Science Oxford</title>
      <link>/2020/01/19/year-3-trip-on-the-30th-jan-to-science-oxford/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 17:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/19/year-3-trip-on-the-30th-jan-to-science-oxford/</guid>
      <description>Dear year 3EE parents,
We are pleased to let you know there will be a school trip to Science Oxford on Thursday 30th January to carry out some hands on experiments and observe other scientific phenomena. https://scienceoxford.com/centre/visitor-information/
The coaches will depart promptly at 9am. Children will require a packed lunch and water bottle that day, please ensure they have a small rucksack or bag to carry this in.
We will need two parent helpers for the trip so let me know if you are free and would like to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spelling lists and homeowork for 3EE for the year</title>
      <link>/2020/01/17/spelling-lists-and-homeowork-for-3ee-for-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/17/spelling-lists-and-homeowork-for-3ee-for-the-year/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
Please find attached the spelling lists for the year. Each Monday we will test we will test 10 common exception words and 10 words which follow the spelling rule for that week. Some weeks the rule is &amp;lsquo;common exception words&amp;rsquo; so the children will have an additional 10 CE words which are listed in the table and stuck in their homework books. Due to an error made last term we will test aut week 5 and 6 words when we would expect to do spr week 5 and 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading book tomorrow</title>
      <link>/2020/01/08/reading-book-tomorrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 21:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/08/reading-book-tomorrow/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
I hope you all had a really nice time at Christmas.
Tomorrow we will start reading the book &amp;ldquo;Cartas a Raton Perez&amp;rdquo; in class. In case you bought the book, please remind your child to bring it tomorrow.
Thanks
Sofia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE Power maths workbook 3A</title>
      <link>/2019/12/09/3ee-power-maths-workbook-3a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 19:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/09/3ee-power-maths-workbook-3a/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
This term’s maths workbooks should have come home today with your child as we no longer need them in school (we are moving onto the next term’s workbook). Please do not be alarmed that they are not completely filled in and some lessons appear to be missed - this is in part because they are designed for schools who have 5 maths lessons in English each week. It is also because we use other resources to carry out investigations and work on understanding concepts so not everything is recorded in this workbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas song</title>
      <link>/2019/12/01/christmas-song/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 13:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/01/christmas-song/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
Please see below the link for the Christmas song that we are practising in class for the concert, in case someone can&#39;t find it. It can be found on youtube under the name &amp;ldquo;Campana sobre campana, Juana, Villancico Clasico (Animado) - Canticuentos.
  I also asked them that if they have small bell/sleigh bell it would be good if they could bring it with them for the song.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish topics, websites and reading books</title>
      <link>/2019/12/01/spanish-topics-websites-and-reading-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 11:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/01/spanish-topics-websites-and-reading-books/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
Some parents wanted to know the topics we will be learning this year in Spanish. You can see this below, so you can also support them with this at home:
 Family Descriptions Pats of the body Jobs Christmas in Spain Clothes The weather Nationalities, where people are from Carnival Our town Shops Plants, life cycle of plants Animals, habitats, life cycles Semana Santa, Easter in Spain Food, in the restaurant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE - chance to borrow glockenspiel to practise Christmas song</title>
      <link>/2019/11/25/3ee-chance-to-borrow-glockenspiel-to-practise-christmas-song/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/25/3ee-chance-to-borrow-glockenspiel-to-practise-christmas-song/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
If you would like your child to borrow a glockenspiel overnight to practise for our Christmas concert please email me to confirm this and I will allow them to take it home. It must be returned the next day so that other children can have a chance to borrow it in turn. Also we need ALL the glockenspiels in school for rehearsing as we will be doing a short practice each day and there are only just enough for one between two children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE - Updated spelling tests, TT rockstars update</title>
      <link>/2019/11/21/3ee-updated-spelling-tests-tt-rockstars-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 21:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/21/3ee-updated-spelling-tests-tt-rockstars-update/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
It was lovely to see so many of you yesterday for parents evening. On the back of our discussions I will be adjusting the spelling tests a little so that they have two short tests of 10 words each. The second test will be 10 randomly selected spellings from the list they stick in each week. These lists follow particular spelling rules. However as many children need to secure the foundations of their spellings this year the first short test of 10 words will be common exception words (those words which crop up regularly in reading and writing and often do not follow easy phonic patterns).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE maths homework 2019-2020 - times tables</title>
      <link>/2019/11/19/3ee-maths-homework-2019-2020-times-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 22:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/19/3ee-maths-homework-2019-2020-times-tables/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
The children&#39;s English maths challenge this year for homework is to learn their times tables facts and related division facts. Hopefully Times Tables Rockstars has proved helpful for some, if you would like some non-screen options there are plenty of card game sets available with the question on one side and answer on the other. We even made our own individual sets for 4x and divide by 4 in class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE Parents evening location - room 99 NOT the classroom</title>
      <link>/2019/11/18/3ee-parents-evening-location-room-99-not-the-classroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 21:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/18/3ee-parents-evening-location-room-99-not-the-classroom/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents,
Please come to room 99 for parents evening appointments, not the classroom. As we will be starting appointments when the classroom is in use then all of the meetings will be in room 99 which is in the hostel block, opposite the Thame Lane reception office. There will be a few chairs outside to wait on.
Many thanks,
Ruthy Trevitt and Sofia Morton</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matt Brown author visit on Tuesday 19th Nov</title>
      <link>/2019/11/17/matt-brown-author-visit-on-tuesday-19th-nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 08:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/17/matt-brown-author-visit-on-tuesday-19th-nov/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents,
The author Matt Brown will be visiting some of our junior classes on Tuesday 19th November. This is a rescheduled visit so if your child purchased a Matt Brown book a few weeks ago and would like it signed please do bring it in and he can sign it on the day. If your child would like to purchase any further titles at a discounted price please use the online payment method detailed in the attached letter or bring the correct cash or cheque and a completed form (attached) to buy the book on the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theatre Trip on Monday 18th November</title>
      <link>/2019/11/13/theatre-trip-on-monday-18th-november/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/13/theatre-trip-on-monday-18th-november/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents,
This is a gentle reminder that we have a year 3 visit to the Theatre this coming Monday. Please remember to give your child a packed lunch which we will be eating when we return to school.
If your child suffers from travel sickness please send an email to your class teacher to let them know.
Could parent helpers please sign in at the main reception and then make your way to the classroom to meet up with the teacher and read the risk assessment before the class departs for the trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE notices in an easier to digest format</title>
      <link>/2019/11/12/3ee-notices-in-an-easier-to-digest-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/12/3ee-notices-in-an-easier-to-digest-format/</guid>
      <description>Please find the notices sent earlier today in a format that is easier to digest and print. No new information just an additional format.
Many thanks,
Ruthy
[![](/images/Dear 3EE parents.png)](/docs/Dear 3EE parents.docx) [![](/images/English Christmas Song 2019.png)](/docs/English Christmas Song 2019.docx)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE trips, authors, parents meetings, PE shoes, concert</title>
      <link>/2019/11/12/3ee-trips-authors-parents-meetings-pe-shoes-concert/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 08:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/12/3ee-trips-authors-parents-meetings-pe-shoes-concert/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
There are five points of information for you in this email: trips, author visit, parents evening, PE shoes, and the Christmas concert. We hope you find it helpful and apologise for the short notice of some of the details.
Many thanks,
Ruthy Trevitt and Sofia Morton
 1) TRIPS
a) Pantomime is next Monday, please provide a packed lunch for your child. Parent helpers for this trip have been arranged, they will be our regular weekly volunteers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Times table rockstars - improved for your children</title>
      <link>/2019/10/31/times-table-rockstars-improved-for-your-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 11:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/31/times-table-rockstars-improved-for-your-children/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
I have just improved the set up of Times tables rockstars so that all pupils have the 2, 5, 10 and 3 x table questions available on their games. Please have a go on this website and see what you think - our free trial as a school ends in a week and we need to evaluate the service to see if it is a good idea for the school to subscribe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Author visit Tuesday 22nd October - discounted books available</title>
      <link>/2019/10/19/author-visit-tuesday-22nd-october-discounted-books-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/19/author-visit-tuesday-22nd-october-discounted-books-available/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents,
This coming Tuesday, 22nd October, the children’s book author Matt Brown is visiting to talk to your child’s class. It will be an opportunity for the children to find out about the creative art of writing. Find out more by reading a first chapter at https://usborne.com/browse-books/catalogue/product/1/8029/compton-valance-the-most-powerful-boy-in-the-universe/ or visit Matt Brown’s website https://www.mattbrownwriter.com/
If your child would like to benefit from a discounted price on some of Matt Brown’s books they can bring in a cheque or cash and a completed form on Monday or Tuesday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE parents meetings, Christmas cards, violins, author visits, museum artefacts, class reps</title>
      <link>/2019/10/02/3ee-parents-meetings-christmas-cards-violins-author-visits-museum-artefacts-class-reps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 15:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/02/3ee-parents-meetings-christmas-cards-violins-author-visits-museum-artefacts-class-reps/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
As yet we have no class reps, this is a shared role and could be shared I am sure between more than two people but without any reps it will make raising money for the class at the Christmas fair and organising other events quite tricky. It doesn&#39;t need to be a big role, make of it what you choose but it would be really helpful to have some reps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE curriculum plan 2019-2020 and trips</title>
      <link>/2019/09/29/3ee-curriculum-plan-2019-2020-and-trips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 21:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/29/3ee-curriculum-plan-2019-2020-and-trips/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
Please find attached the curriculum overview for this year (also called our long term plan). There may be slight variations on this as we adapt to the interests of the children and to events.
Lastly, although dates are not confirmed yet we should be taking part in the following experiences and trips:
  Visit from the Abingdon museum to look at the 1950s, 1960s and 1970s</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading books</title>
      <link>/2019/09/28/reading-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 10:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/28/reading-books/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
I think some parents have bought the books I mentioned. Thanks a lot for this, it is much appreciated and the children will benefit. It would be good to know what books the children have as I would like to use them in the class with them.
For this reason I would appreciate if they could bring the book(s) they&#39;ve got in to class with their names on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading and resources</title>
      <link>/2019/09/18/reading-and-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 19:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/18/reading-and-resources/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
I hope this email finds everyone well. As I mentioned at parents evening, for children that finish reading the class book quickly and would like to read a longer book, I would suggest some books from this website:
More difficult reading (8- 10 years old): link
Less difficult reading (6- 8 years old): link
They are really good as they have lots of activities and resources on the internet for each book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>/2019/09/15/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 10:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/15/reading/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents
This year we will be working with some books to read in class and do some activities from. It would be good if they can continue reading them at home at the same time as it would help their comprehension and vocabulary.
See below the list of reading books we will be using each term if you would like to get them.
Autumn:
 Ricardo y el dinosaurio rojo   Cuando me converti en lobo  Spring:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE information meeting for parents and English reading books</title>
      <link>/2019/09/04/3ee-information-meeting-for-parents-and-english-reading-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 21:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/04/3ee-information-meeting-for-parents-and-english-reading-books/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
Sofia and I would like to invite you to an information evening on Wednesday 18th September. You are welcome to come up the classroom stairs at 4.45pm to look around the classroom, locker room and browse the reading books (suggestions of missing book genres or titles are welcome). The meeting itself will run from 5 until 5.45pm. This is an opportunity for you to ask questions about anything you are unsure of or things you didn&#39;t find in the information sheet sent out earlier this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headshot/portrait photos of 3EE for display</title>
      <link>/2019/09/03/headshot-portrait-photos-of-3ee-for-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 07:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/03/headshot-portrait-photos-of-3ee-for-display/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents,
Apologies for a second email, please could we request the children to bring in a clear photo of themselves: headshots would be perfect but any picture where we can see their lovely faces is great. We would like to make a little display about ourselves to help all the staff who work with 3EE get to know the children quickly especially as we have a violin teacher and sports coach in addition to our 2 teachers and 2 TAs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3EE information for 2019-2020</title>
      <link>/2019/09/02/3ee-information-for-2019-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 23:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/02/3ee-information-for-2019-2020/</guid>
      <description>Dear 3EE parents,
We look forward to getting to know you better and will be delighted to see you at the information evening to be held in the next few weeks. In advance of this meeting please find nearly all the information you will need about this year. For the small things we may have forgotten please let us know in advance of the information evening so we can provide you with answers at the meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advance welcome to 3EE</title>
      <link>/2019/07/02/advance-welcome-to-3ee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 23:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/07/02/advance-welcome-to-3ee/</guid>
      <description>Dear soon-to-be 3EE parents,
It was lovely to meet the class last week, we are looking forward to getting to know them, and your good selves, over the forthcoming academic year.
You may be wondering &amp;quot;what&#39;s new for year 3?&amp;quot; Well thankfully, in terms of settling in, not too much. We have lunch a bit later which means a longer morning and shorter afternoon. Each week the class&amp;rsquo; music lesson involves learning string instruments (cello and violin) and if you agree to it the children can take the instruments home to practice with the help of an interactive music website.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>