<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homework on Europa Español-English Class 2016</title>
    <link>/categories/homework/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homework on Europa Español-English Class 2016</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 19:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/homework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings</title>
      <link>/2018/12/07/spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 19:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/07/spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Your children have been a joy to teach this week. They have learned lots about how to make slime and how to choose which materials would be best for an umbrella or a bouncy ball. They have painted pine cones from the tree in forest schools and worked with clay in art. If you are cutting up pizzas ask them if fractions need to be equal. They know about halves, quarters and thirds … and quite a bit more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings and song</title>
      <link>/2018/11/30/spellings-and-song/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/30/spellings-and-song/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents.
Your children have done amazingly again this week. You should be very proud of them. They have learned to use the bar model to find missing numbers in subtraction stories. They have made designs for 50 pound notes. They have researched scientists and made dens in the forest. And more. Please find attached a song which they are learning for the concert. It would be wonderful if they could secretly practice at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half term Spanish Homework</title>
      <link>/2018/10/17/half-term-spanish-homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/17/half-term-spanish-homework/</guid>
      <description>Dear parents and guardians,
The children have been very busy at the biginning of this first term learning some words and vocabulary to provide a context for future learning (getting to know the school, classroom supplies, parts of the body, adjectives, food, etc.). Please, help them keep doing so by doing their homework and finding opportunities to ask them about what they have learnt at school.
This week we are sending the first book in a bag as reading homework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings for Ladybirds</title>
      <link>/2018/10/11/spellings-for-ladybirds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/11/spellings-for-ladybirds/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Thanks for all your help in supporting your child&amp;rsquo;s learning of spellings last week, they were thrilled to show their learning in class today.
The words to learn for the coming week are: 1. made 2. came 3. same 4. take 5. safe 6. five 7. ride 8. door 9. poor 10. floor
As you can see, this week the pattern is words containing the vowel phonemes using split digraphs a_e and i_e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings for test next Thursday</title>
      <link>/2018/10/04/spellings-for-test-next-thursday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/04/spellings-for-test-next-thursday/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Many thanks for supporting your child in learning their spellings. This week’s words to learn practice the ai and oi sound. The last two words are from the tricky word list.
 rain wait train paid oil join coin point Mr Mrs  Have fun together playing with sounds.
Warmest wishes,
Liz Cook</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings for next week</title>
      <link>/2018/09/27/spellings-for-next-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 17:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/27/spellings-for-next-week/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents and Guardians,
Thank you for working so hard to help your children learn their spellings last week. We had a test in class today and they were thrilled to share with each other the ingenious ways they had practised.
For the coming week the spellings are the words for numbers from eleven to twenty.
 eleven twelve thirteen fourteen fifteen sixteen seventeen eighteen nineteen twenty  Have fun with your children in rainbow letters, air writing, in the car &amp;hellip; the test is in school next Thursday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings for 2EE</title>
      <link>/2018/09/22/spellings-for-2ee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 17:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/22/spellings-for-2ee/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents
Please find below the spellings for next Thursday’s spelling test in Class 2EE.
 one two three four five six seven eight nine ten  The children completed a spelling assessment yesterday and I will be marking it over the weekend so that we can provide differentiated levels of spellings from next week.
Apologies for the delay in these reaching you, I thought schoolbase had sent this to you previously.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>