<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>English on Europa Español-English Class 2016</title>
    <link>/tags/english/</link>
    <description>Recent content in English on Europa Español-English Class 2016</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 17:18:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings for 2EE</title>
      <link>/2018/09/22/spellings-for-2ee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 17:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/22/spellings-for-2ee/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents
Please find below the spellings for next Thursday’s spelling test in Class 2EE.
 one two three four five six seven eight nine ten  The children completed a spelling assessment yesterday and I will be marking it over the weekend so that we can provide differentiated levels of spellings from next week.
Apologies for the delay in these reaching you, I thought schoolbase had sent this to you previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documents from phonics screening meeting</title>
      <link>/2018/04/27/documents-from-phonics-screening-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 16:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/27/documents-from-phonics-screening-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents
As discussed at the meeting we are sending you the presentation that we shared with you and the list of sample words, which can be used for practise at home. The words include all the sounds that we have covered this year - the phase 3 and 5 sounds.
Download presentation
Download sample words
Unfortunately the presentation becomes slightly corrupted on saving, however all the information can be read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonics screening notes</title>
      <link>/2018/04/25/phonics-screening-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 22:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/25/phonics-screening-notes/</guid>
      <description>Hi,
I took some notes at the phonics screening meeting this evening - I thought they might be useful to share with the whole class group via email.
The teachers are going to circulate the powerpoint slides from the meeting and some examples of the words they will have to read,
 Phonics Screening is a national &amp;lsquo;test&amp;rsquo; that takes place in Year 1 in the second week in June.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parents&#39; meeting regarding Year 1 phonics screening</title>
      <link>/2018/04/13/parents-meeting-regarding-year-1-phonics-screening/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/13/parents-meeting-regarding-year-1-phonics-screening/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
We would like to invite you to a short meeting at 6-6:30 pm on Wednesday the 25th of April regarding the statutory Year 1 phonics screening which will take place in early June. We plan to meet in the Drama Studio at the bottom of the large tower block.
At the meeting we will outline the nature of the the screening program and suggest ways that you can support your child with their phonics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>