<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>English on Europa Español-English Class 2016</title>
    <link>/tags/english/</link>
    <description>Recent content in English on Europa Español-English Class 2016</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 18:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun Run, Toilet Rolls and Spellings</title>
      <link>/2019/06/14/fun-run-toilet-rolls-and-spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/14/fun-run-toilet-rolls-and-spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
We have had fun this week developing a play about the rainforest, making beautiful poetry using the word if and creating illustrations for a special card. We have played with in-between numbers, built towers as teams and each child has lit their own forest school fire with a flint and steel.
Please support your child in learning to spell these words with suffixes:
 enjoy
 enjoyed
 enjoyment</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy holidays</title>
      <link>/2019/05/24/happy-holidays/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 18:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/24/happy-holidays/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
This is just to wish you a very happy half term with your children, who definitely deserve a rest. They have worked incredibly hard this month. We have had a lot of fun learning together.
This week they learnt about the water cycle and made three kinds of clouds. They wrote wonderful stories, created cubes with matchsticks, lay in the orchard and used their senses to make journey sticks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Film and Spellings</title>
      <link>/2019/05/17/film-and-spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 16:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/17/film-and-spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
The children made a film this week about the rainforest – please do take the time to watch it here
https://spark.adobe.com/video/cE4mCDojIDlYQ
 We had fun cooking pizzas on the Forest Schools fire, creating stories, measuring our feet and writing about the seasons.
Please do listen to your children reading aloud to you this week. This week’s spellings are:
 who
 would
 could
 should
 many</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No English homework other than reading this weekend</title>
      <link>/2019/05/10/no-english-homework-other-than-reading-this-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 16:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/10/no-english-homework-other-than-reading-this-weekend/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Your children have worked super hard this week and deserve a weekend off - so no English homework this week other than reading their book to you. Hopefully this will give you time to enjoy reading a book for pleasure together.
We had a wonderful day today celebrating our international links. The children made complex flags showing all the different countries they felt connected with. They found the countries on a map and made a collaborative jigsaw of the whole world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework and running with the wind</title>
      <link>/2019/05/03/homework-and-running-with-the-wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 16:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/03/homework-and-running-with-the-wind/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
We have had fun this week making wind socks and weather vanes. Your child should be able to tell you how wind is made and how we can measure it and find its direction. In English we began to learn about the life of Beatrix Potter. In Maths we made posters explaining our understanding of operations and the children showed off their wonderful Maths as a Birthday treat for M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework and running with the wind</title>
      <link>/2019/04/26/homework-and-running-with-the-wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 16:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/26/homework-and-running-with-the-wind/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
It has been great to see the children again this week. In Forest Schools they made elder necklaces and in English they wrote about a special place. They thought up questions about our new topic of the weather. They played coins, gave change for cakes and learnt how to answer word questions in Maths. In RE we started to explore Islam as our third religion this year.
For homework this week there are no extra spellings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campfire photos and homework</title>
      <link>/2019/04/05/2019-04-05t173800-campfire-photos-and-homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 17:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/05/2019-04-05t173800-campfire-photos-and-homework/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
The children have celebrated their wonderful hard work and creativity this term with a well-deserved jewel party today after bananas and chocolate cooked on the Forest School campfire. Thank you very much to all those parents who provided such wonderful party food for them.
As the Year 2 assessments come during the month of May, it would be great if you could gently support your child with some learning reminders in the holidays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings and falconry</title>
      <link>/2019/03/29/2019-03-29t171100-spellings-and-falconry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 17:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/29/2019-03-29t171100-spellings-and-falconry/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
I hope the children have already told you about the wonderful day we had yesterday at Millets Falconry. They held a northern white faced owl called “Quintessa” and learnt that owls have different coloured eyes depending on when they hunt. Please find photos attached (the app has duplicated some, apologies).
Today they planted sunflower seeds – one for Mum and one for themselves as a gift for Mother’s on Sunday’s UK Mother’s day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings and Important Information re Millets Falconry Trip</title>
      <link>/2019/03/22/spellings-and-important-information-re-millets-falconry-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 17:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/22/spellings-and-important-information-re-millets-falconry-trip/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
This week the children have planted cress and set up a test to see if water and light affect its growth. They have explored fractions of amounts, painted symmetrical butterfly wings and turned shapes clockwise and anticlockwise. They have written their Mai Ling story and explored chromatography in forest schools.
Next week we are looking forward to going to see the birds in Millets Falconry on Thursday. The trip will leave school at 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings and story</title>
      <link>/2019/03/15/spellings-and-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 16:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/15/spellings-and-story/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Science week has been fun! The children used microscopes on Wednesday, assisted by a research scientist Oxford University. On Thursday they learnt about animal behaviour from Luca’s Mum and loved hearing about positive rewards helping rescue animals learn to behave. In Maths they have made 3D shapes and in English they have learnt how to tell the Chinese story of Mai Ling. Please do ask them to tell you the story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings and yoghurt pots</title>
      <link>/2019/03/09/spellings-and-yoghurt-pots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/09/spellings-and-yoghurt-pots/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
We had a great World Book Day filled week this week and the children all developed their own imaginary characters, which they illustrated and described for the school Book Day competition. They planted beans to grow hydroponically on the window and identified plants in Forest Schools. In Maths, they played with fractions by folding paper and remembered that they are equal parts of a whole.
Next week is Science Week and we are looking forward to using microscopes and exploring animal behaviour with visitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings and SATs papers</title>
      <link>/2019/03/02/spellings-and-sats-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 09:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/02/spellings-and-sats-papers/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Class 2EE had a great week this week, I hope they have already told you about the helicopter seeds they made to understand seed dispersal, plant art with cardboard pieces, measuring g, kg, ml and litres and writing about their magic gardens. We welcomed a new child to our class, Ariadne joined us just in time to celebrate her birthday.
Spellings this week are the or sound spelt as a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SATs info eve tomorrow 5pm, Book Fair competition and fancy dress</title>
      <link>/2019/02/26/sats-info-eve-tomorrow-5pm-book-fair-competition-and-fancy-dress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/26/sats-info-eve-tomorrow-5pm-book-fair-competition-and-fancy-dress/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
I hope you had a relaxing and happy half term. This is just a note to say I am looking forward to seeing you for the SATs INFORMATION EVENING in 2EE classroom tomorrow at 5pm.
Next week the BOOK FAIR will be held in the chapel every day from 15.45 until 16.15. Please come and support the school by buying a book if you can.
Linked to the book fair there is a COMPETITION to design an A4 extraordinary/interesting word poster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poet&#39;s ribbons and Times Table certificate</title>
      <link>/2019/02/15/poets-ribbons-and-times-table-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 16:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/15/poets-ribbons-and-times-table-certificate/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
This week the children wrote number poems, baked bread on a camp fire, learnt about penguins and played maths games with shapes. There are no spellings for half term, but two challenges.
Challenge 1 – POET’S RIBBON
To learn a poem by heart. Any child able to share their poem by heart after the break will win a poet&amp;rsquo;s ribbon for their book bag. I attach a few poems to choose from but any poem they love will do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dates for your diary and spellings</title>
      <link>/2019/02/08/dates-for-your-diary-and-spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/08/dates-for-your-diary-and-spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
We have had fun this week making food chains, finding out about left over M&amp;amp;Ms, writing colour poems, learning about Hanukkah, playing Guess Who and making a Forest School Canopy.
Words to learn for spelling this week are:
 fly
 sky
 pie
 mice
  5.high
6.might
7.night
8.tights
9.sigh
10.sight
You child has brought home some of these on light bulbs to play with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings</title>
      <link>/2019/01/25/spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 19:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/25/spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
The children have had a busy week creating habitat posters, playing with 5 x tables, making handprints in the forest, dividing up cookies, modelling animals in clay and thinking from inside the head of a robin, crab, frog or squirrel. The classroom is full of their wonderful creations.
This week’s words to learn for spellings are:
 tie
 pie
 cry
 try
 dry
 cried</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings</title>
      <link>/2019/01/18/spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 18:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/18/spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Your children have written owl books, multiplied with arrays, painted with straws, laid footprint traps, explored habitats, learnt about Judaism and more this week. They’ve been busy!
On Thursday we visited the Library and the children were invited to take a book home. I have a list of the books they have borrowed. There is no pressure at all for the children to read the books, they may enjoy you reading to them or they may just want to dip in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No spellings!</title>
      <link>/2018/12/14/no-spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 18:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/14/no-spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
The children have worked so hard this week I think we should not do a spelling test next week.
It was lovely to see some of you at the concert on Monday and on Wednesday evening. Many thanks for your generosity to Snr Ruiz and I - I have some very lovely presents to put under the tree.
Some of you asked me to send you a copy of the tricky words which your child should be able to spell by the end of the year in their own writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings</title>
      <link>/2018/12/07/spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 19:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/07/spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Your children have been a joy to teach this week. They have learned lots about how to make slime and how to choose which materials would be best for an umbrella or a bouncy ball. They have painted pine cones from the tree in forest schools and worked with clay in art. If you are cutting up pizzas ask them if fractions need to be equal. They know about halves, quarters and thirds … and quite a bit more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings and song</title>
      <link>/2018/11/30/spellings-and-song/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/30/spellings-and-song/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents.
Your children have done amazingly again this week. You should be very proud of them. They have learned to use the bar model to find missing numbers in subtraction stories. They have made designs for 50 pound notes. They have researched scientists and made dens in the forest. And more. Please find attached a song which they are learning for the concert. It would be wonderful if they could secretly practice at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest School and Spellings</title>
      <link>/2018/11/22/forest-school-and-spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/22/forest-school-and-spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
The children had a fascinating time today playing with real money hot off the press from De La Rue.
  They have brought home a pencil made of old bank notes to show you. Tomorrow we will be enjoying testing out building with materials to see if they are waterproof in Forest Schools. Please do make sure that your child has suitable clothing. It will be cold and possibly wet Gloves, hats, warm coats and waterproof trousers are ideal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building houses with materials</title>
      <link>/2018/11/15/building-houses-with-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/15/building-houses-with-materials/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
I thought you might like to see some pictures from the building work today. The children worked immensely hard responding to a brief, designing, budgeting, building, testing and adapting their houses. They learnt a lot about working in teams, keeping within a timeframe and learning from mistakes. I hope they mentioned it to you. They should be very proud of their hard work. Attached are two compilation photos, excuse the mix being a little rushed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings</title>
      <link>/2018/11/15/spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 11:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/15/spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
The children are having a great day building houses for the three little pigs today. They are working as teams to design, budget, build and test their houses to see if they can withstand the wolf&amp;rsquo;s blowing. This is why we did our spelling test early yesterday.
The spellings to learn for next week are as follows:
 food
 moon
 school
 good
 book
 took</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings and fireworks Poem</title>
      <link>/2018/11/09/spellings-and-fireworks-poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 17:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/09/spellings-and-fireworks-poem/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
This week’s words to learn are: 1. head 2. bread 3. meant 4. road 5. coat 6. coach 7. child 8. children 9. wild 10. climb
The first five words will remind the children that when &amp;ldquo;two vowels go together, the first one says its name&amp;rdquo;. The last five words are tricky words from the Year 2 list.
I am also attaching the fireworks poem which the children wrote this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest Schools</title>
      <link>/2018/11/08/forest-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 12:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/08/forest-schools/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents
Re: Outdoor Learning in Year 2
Year 2 are being introduced to the principles of Forest School. We are lucky to have this facility on our site and a member of staff who has trained as a Forest school Leader.
Forest School uses the outdoor environment to support children’s learning across the whole curriculum. The activities specifically follow and enhance the learning from inside the classroom, with a very hands-on approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings</title>
      <link>/2018/11/02/spellings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 16:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/02/spellings/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Many thanks for supporting your child in learning this week’s words to learn to spell:
 see green week sea each read find kind mind behind  Thanks too to all those of you who are reading on a nightly basis with the children, it makes such a difference. Please do try and ensure that English reading books come back into school each week on a Wednesday so that we can change them for a new one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Comprehension</title>
      <link>/2018/11/01/reading-comprehension/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 17:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/01/reading-comprehension/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Today we have sent home a reading comprehension book to your child as part of this week&amp;rsquo;s homework. Please would you support your child in helping them read the first poem Big Red Boots on page 4 and answering the questions on page 5 as well as they can. This will be challenging for some children as it is a very formal lay out and asks them to answer specific questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half term</title>
      <link>/2018/10/19/half-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/19/half-term/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
We have had a great week with your bright children. I hope they tell you about some of the things they have learnt this week. Ask them about toasting marshmallows in Forest School, or writing instructions about how to make a sandwich &amp;hellip; and then making one. They can tell you about how c and g are scared of i,e and y. They may even be able to fill you in on how to find out the classes favourite sandwich - as a bar chart, or a tally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings for Ladybirds</title>
      <link>/2018/10/11/spellings-for-ladybirds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/11/spellings-for-ladybirds/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Thanks for all your help in supporting your child&amp;rsquo;s learning of spellings last week, they were thrilled to show their learning in class today.
The words to learn for the coming week are: 1. made 2. came 3. same 4. take 5. safe 6. five 7. ride 8. door 9. poor 10. floor
As you can see, this week the pattern is words containing the vowel phonemes using split digraphs a_e and i_e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Film shown in assembly today</title>
      <link>/2018/10/10/film-shown-in-assembly-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/10/film-shown-in-assembly-today/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Your children&amp;rsquo;s work was shown in assembly today and I thought you might like to see it. Class 2EE made beautiful film riddles using their senses and lots of adjectives - they described two places in the school and challenged the other children to guess where they had been.
To see the films just click on the link below or cut and paste it into your internet browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings for test next Thursday</title>
      <link>/2018/10/04/spellings-for-test-next-thursday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/04/spellings-for-test-next-thursday/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
Many thanks for supporting your child in learning their spellings. This week’s words to learn practice the ai and oi sound. The last two words are from the tricky word list.
 rain wait train paid oil join coin point Mr Mrs  Have fun together playing with sounds.
Warmest wishes,
Liz Cook</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings for next week</title>
      <link>/2018/09/27/spellings-for-next-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 17:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/27/spellings-for-next-week/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents and Guardians,
Thank you for working so hard to help your children learn their spellings last week. We had a test in class today and they were thrilled to share with each other the ingenious ways they had practised.
For the coming week the spellings are the words for numbers from eleven to twenty.
 eleven twelve thirteen fourteen fifteen sixteen seventeen eighteen nineteen twenty  Have fun with your children in rainbow letters, air writing, in the car &amp;hellip; the test is in school next Thursday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spellings for 2EE</title>
      <link>/2018/09/22/spellings-for-2ee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 17:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/22/spellings-for-2ee/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents
Please find below the spellings for next Thursday’s spelling test in Class 2EE.
 one two three four five six seven eight nine ten  The children completed a spelling assessment yesterday and I will be marking it over the weekend so that we can provide differentiated levels of spellings from next week.
Apologies for the delay in these reaching you, I thought schoolbase had sent this to you previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documents from phonics screening meeting</title>
      <link>/2018/04/27/documents-from-phonics-screening-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 16:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/27/documents-from-phonics-screening-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents
As discussed at the meeting we are sending you the presentation that we shared with you and the list of sample words, which can be used for practise at home. The words include all the sounds that we have covered this year - the phase 3 and 5 sounds.
Download presentation
Download sample words
Unfortunately the presentation becomes slightly corrupted on saving, however all the information can be read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonics screening notes</title>
      <link>/2018/04/25/phonics-screening-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 22:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/25/phonics-screening-notes/</guid>
      <description>Hi,
I took some notes at the phonics screening meeting this evening - I thought they might be useful to share with the whole class group via email.
The teachers are going to circulate the powerpoint slides from the meeting and some examples of the words they will have to read,
 Phonics Screening is a national &amp;lsquo;test&amp;rsquo; that takes place in Year 1 in the second week in June.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parents&#39; meeting regarding Year 1 phonics screening</title>
      <link>/2018/04/13/parents-meeting-regarding-year-1-phonics-screening/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/13/parents-meeting-regarding-year-1-phonics-screening/</guid>
      <description>Dear Parents,
We would like to invite you to a short meeting at 6-6:30 pm on Wednesday the 25th of April regarding the statutory Year 1 phonics screening which will take place in early June. We plan to meet in the Drama Studio at the bottom of the large tower block.
At the meeting we will outline the nature of the the screening program and suggest ways that you can support your child with their phonics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>